​​​ ​Months ago, I put a million dollars ​ ​​
​​ ​in this vault​ ​​
​​​ ​and then on a Super Bowl commercial…​ ​​
​​​ ​Close it up, boys!​ ​​
​​​ ​I said whoever solved ​ ​​
​​ ​a hundred puzzles first,​ ​​
​​​ ​spread all across the internet,​ ​​
​​​ ​would win the money inside.​ ​​
​​​ ​And out of millions of people, one ​ ​​
​​ ​human cracked the code.​ ​​
​​​ ​And I'm gonna show you guys ​ ​​
​​ ​EXACTLY how he did it.​ ​​
​​​ ​BOYS!! Pointer me.​ ​​
​​​ ​YEAHH!​ ​​
​​​ ​Now throw me my super expensive--​ ​​
​​​ ​BANGG!​ ​​
​​​ ​CRASHhHH!​ ​​
​​​ ​Yeaah!!​ ​​
​​​ ​Lap-- top.​ ​​
​​​ ​To have won a million dollars,​ ​​
​​​ ​you first had to watch ​ ​​
​​ ​my Super Bowl teaser​ ​​
​​​ ​titled "Watch My Super Bowl Ad ​ ​​
​​ ​to Win a Million Dollars."​ ​​
​​​ ​If you went in the description ​ ​​
​​ ​and clicked on this playlist,​ ​​
​​​ ​then looked at the pinned comments ​ ​​
​​ ​of all of these videos,​ ​​
​​​ ​you would get nine puzzles,​ ​​
​​​ ​and if you completed them, ​ ​​
​​ ​you'd receive your first answer,​ ​​
​​​ ​which was: "Every challenge leads towards ​ ​​
​​ ​location name somewhere around world."​ ​​
​​​ ​Great!​ ​​
​​​ ​After hours, I just taught you ​ ​​
​​ ​how to play the game,​ ​​
​​​ ​and this…​ ​​
​​​ ​is the actual puzzle.​ ​​
​​​ ​And to win the million dollars,​ ​​
​​​ ​you needed to find ​ ​​
​​ ​ninety-one locations​ ​​
​​​ ​hidden throughout all ​ ​​
​​ ​of these clues.​ ​​
​​​ ​So let's get into it, ​ ​​
​​ ​starting with…​ ​​
​​​ ​my Super Bowl commercial.​ ​​
​​​ ​I just put one million dollars ​ ​​
​​ ​inside this vault.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you were to group and add these ​ ​​
​​ ​bright colored bills in the vault together​ ​​
​​​ ​and then match those numbers ​ ​​
​​ ​to letters in the alphabet,​ ​​
​​​ ​you get "CASH TENT,"​ ​​
​​​ ​which sounds like Tashkent, Uzbekistan,​ ​​
​​​ ​which would be your first ​ ​​
​​ ​of twelve locations.​ ​​
​​​ ​But do you remember when I said:​ ​​
​​​ ​"Then go win a MILLION dollars!"​ ​​
​​​ ​I was wearing a belt ​ ​​
​​ ​with very special X's.​ ​​
​​​ ​Whyyy were they special??​ ​​
​​​ ​These X's were actually wired ​ ​​
​​ ​color code pairs.​ ​​
​​​ ​And because there's ​ ​​
​​ ​twenty-five of them,​ ​​
​​​ ​you could map them ​ ​​
​​ ​to the alphabet,​ ​​
​​​ ​giving you…​ ​​
​​​ ​Lima, Peru, ​ ​​
​​ ​your second location.​ ​​
​​​ ​The third was the golden vault door.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you match these numbers and dots ​ ​​
​​ ​to the international Scrabble lexicon,​ ​​
​​​ ​the message would spell out,​ ​​
​​​ ​"He funded a hospital in this site of ​ ​​
​​ ​last year's Scrabble championship,"​ ​​
​​​ ​which was in Accra, Ghana.​ ​​
​​​ ​♪ la laa LA ♪​ ​​
​​​ ​♪ heEYY! Oyee! AYE! ♪​ ​​
​​​ ​For the fourth puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​this bulb is flashing ​ ​​
​​ ​in Morse code,​ ​​
​​​ ​spelling absolutely nothing.​ ​​
​​​ ​But if you play the video ​ ​​
​​ ​in reverse,​ ​​
​​​ ​the Morse code pattern spells "Kabul."​ ​​
​​​ ​And if you take the white tape ​ ​​
​​ ​on the back of my clipboard​ ​​
​​​ ​and overlay it on the front,​ ​​
​​​ ​you'd spell out ​ ​​
​​ ​"Capital of East Nusa Tenggara,"​ ​​
​​​ ​which is Kupang, Indonesia.​ ​​
​​​ ​There are twenty-six ports ​ ​​
​​ ​in this door,​ ​​
​​​ ​and ten lasers fire in a sequence ​ ​​
​​ ​and hit those ports,​ ​​
​​​ ​landing in this order.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you convert these numbers ​ ​​
​​ ​to the alphabet,​ ​​
​​​ ​it spells "laser mixup."​ ​​
​​​ ​And if you mix up the word "laser,"​ ​​
​​​ ​it spells "Arles," ​ ​​
​​ ​as in Arles, France.​ ​​
​​​ ​For the seventh puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​each screen's background color ​ ​​
​​ ​can be read as Base Three Code.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you use the Base Three formula, ​ ​​
​​ ​then convert that to letters,​ ​​
​​​ ​you get "Beast City Hub," ​ ​​
​​ ​built in Toronto, Canada.​ ​​
​​​ ​And if you convert these emojis ​ ​​
​​ ​on my phone to text,​ ​​
​​​ ​the first two letters of each spell ​ ​​
​​ ​the city name of Casablanca,​ ​​
​​​ ​which is in Morocco.​ ​​
​​​ ​And did you catch the smoke bomb?​ ​​
​​​ ​This may look like 1 + 1,​ ​​
​​​ ​but this is an S,​ ​​
​​​ ​this is actually a T,​ ​​
​​​ ​and this is a 1,​ ​​
​​​ ​and the entire thing is yellow,​ ​​
​​​ ​which spells out Yellowstone, Wyoming.​ ​​
​​​ ​And did you see these doors??​ ​​
​​​ ​They have some pretty weird ​ ​​
​​ ​dots on them,​ ​​
​​​ ​but if you overlaid these dots ​ ​​
​​ ​together​ ​​
​​​ ​and counted the numbers ​ ​​
​​ ​from top to bottom,​ ​​
​​​ ​you get these atomic numbers.​ ​​
​​​ ​And if you turn them into element symbols,​ ​​
​​​ ​you get Lahore, Pakistan.​ ​​
​​​ ​But my favorite puzzle was ​ ​​
​​ ​probably this tank.​ ​​
​​​ ​There's a letter "I"​ ​​
​​​ ​and a painted picture of ​ ​​
​​ ​a person screaming.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you sound that out, ​ ​​
​​ ​it sounds like "ice cream."​ ​​
​​​ ​And in 2021,​ ​​
​​​ ​I did a video where I ate ​ ​​
​​ ​a $100,000 golden ice cream.​ ​​
​​​ ​And at the 8:20 mark,​ ​​
​​​ ​there is an image ​ ​​
​​ ​of a receipt​ ​​
​​​ ​which shows 36,348 dollars ​ ​​
​​ ​and 26 cents,​ ​​
​​​ ​which matches the tank.​ ​​
​​​ ​This receipt was for ​ ​​
​​ ​$30,000 Bananas Foster.​ ​​
​​​ ​So why does that matter?​ ​​
​​​ ​Well Bananas Foster was invented ​ ​​
​​ ​in 1951​ ​​
​​​ ​at the Vieux Carré Restaurant ​ ​​
​​ ​in New Orleans, Louisiana.​ ​​
​​​ ​And for the twelfth puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​if you take the closed captioning ​ ​​
​​ ​in the Super Bowl ad,​ ​​
​​​ ​the letters by the dashes​ ​​
​​​ ​spell "Seven Letter Big Lodge."​ ​​
​​​ ​Which is a Tall Inn,​ ​​
​​​ ​AKA Tallinn, Estonia.​ ​​
​​​ ​huhH? Pretty good?​ ​​
​​​ ​CONGRATULATIONS!!​ ​​
​​​ ​Throw yourself a party!​ ​​
​​​ ​You just solved everything in ​ ​​
​​ ​the Super Bowl commercial.​ ​​
​​​ ​What if I told you that's only 10% ​ ​​
​​ ​of the entire puzzle?​ ​​
​​​ ​We're just getting started.​ ​​
​​​ ​Because in my pre-game video,​ ​​
​​​ ​this note on the computer was a puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​this calendar was a puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​this Rubik's Cube obviously was a puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​these street markings were a puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​even this million-dollar check ​ ​​
​​ ​was a puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​this license plate was a puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​and ALL OF THIS ​ ​​
​​ ​was a puzzle as well.​ ​​
​​​ ​There was a lot of puzzles,​ ​​
​​​ ​and if you're wondering ​ ​​
​​ ​how some of them worked,​ ​​
​​​ ​this is a red Rubik's Cube.​ ​​
​​​ ​And if you looked at the commercial,​ ​​
​​​ ​this clue tells us a cube ​ ​​
​​ ​should become a square.​ ​​
​​​ ​So a Red Cube becomes a Red Square,​ ​​
​​​ ​that's a place in Moscow, Russia.​ ​​
​​​ ​And for the crosswalk,​ ​​
​​​ ​there is no crosswalk in the world ​ ​​
​​ ​that should look like this.​ ​​
​​​ ​What about the one that you just showed…?​ ​​
​​​ ​Nolan, you can just… leave.​ ​​
​​​ ​This monitor shows a series of pictures.​ ​​
​​​ ​And the first two letters ​ ​​
​​ ​of these words​ ​​
​​​ ​are compass directions:​ ​​
​​​ ​north, east, south, and west.​ ​​
​​​ ​And I don't know if ​ ​​
​​ ​you guys knew this,​ ​​
​​​ ​but there's actually an alphabet ​ ​​
​​ ​called flag semaphore.​ ​​
​​​ ​So, to get the location ​ ​​
​​ ​from this crosswalk…​ ​​
​​​ ​one arm is already drawn,​ ​​
​​​ ​and the other arm came from ​ ​​
​​ ​the first two letters​ ​​
​​​ ​from those pictures ​ ​​
​​ ​on the monitor.​ ​​
​​​ ​I'm gonna be honest,​ ​​
​​​ ​I have no idea where this was ​ ​​
​​ ​coming from at this point.​ ​​
​​​ ​But if you want to know ​ ​​
​​ ​how to solve​ ​​
​​​ ​the rest of the puzzles in ​ ​​
​​ ​this pre-game video,​ ​​
​​​ ​here's the instructions.​ ​​
​​​ ​The instructions.​ ​​
​​​ ​Yeahh… it's a lot.​ ​​
​​​ ​And since I'm teaching you ​ ​​
​​ ​about puzzles,​ ​​
​​​ ​might as well teach you ​ ​​
​​ ​how to SUBSCRIBE!​ ​​
​​​ ​There's a button right below the video ​ ​​
​​ ​that if you click,​ ​​
​​​ ​it would mean the world to me ​ ​​
​​ ​if you did.​ ​​
​​​ ​And by the way, ​ ​​
​​ ​at the end of this video,​ ​​
​​​ ​I'll tell you how you can solve ​ ​​
​​ ​the puzzle in this video​ ​​
​​​ ​and win $10,000.​ ​​
​​​ ​But that's at the end.​ ​​
​​​ ​Phase three was known as ​ ​​
​​ ​the gift puzzles,​ ​​
​​​ ​where I dropped off this box ​ ​​
​​ ​with a few of my friends.​ ​​
​​​ ​Thank youuu!​ ​​
​​​ ​Thank YOU!​ ​​
​​​ ​He sent me a gift from some ​ ​​
​​ ​Super Bowl commercial?​ ​​
​​​ ​I got a present!!​ ​​
​​​ ​Are you suuure it's not a million dollars?!​ ​​
​​​ ​Each gift had its own ​ ​​
​​ ​unique solution.​ ​​
​​​ ​For instance, Jimmy Fallon got this.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you rearrange the letters ​ ​​
​​ ​in the correct order,​ ​​
​​​ ​this puzzle spells ​ ​​
​​ ​"Jimmy's birth place."​ ​​
​​​ ​Which Jimmy?​ ​​
​​​ ​My birthplace, in Wichita, Kansas.​ ​​
​​​ ​Another clue was hidden in the gift ​ ​​
​​ ​I gave to the Botez sisters.​ ​​
​​​ ​It was a custom chess set ​ ​​
​​ ​with a message​ ​​
​​​ ​that I did not intend ​ ​​
​​ ​to be this creepy.​ ​​
​​​ ​Enjoy this new chess set.​ ​​
​​​ ​Maybe you two can play a game​ ​​
​​​ ​that lasts as long as game six​ ​​
​​​ ​between Magnus Carlsen and Ian ​ ​​
​​ ​Nepomniachtchi.​ ​​
​​​ ​Good chess reference!​ ​​
​​​ ​Go, MrBeast on his chess knowledge.​ ​​
​​​ ​Thanks, Andrea!​ ​​
​​​ ​But that mention wasn't random.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you recreate the final posi--​ ​​
​​​ ​I think we need to find ​ ​​
​​ ​what position it is,​ ​​
​​​ ​set it up, and try to read ​ ​​
​​ ​the message.​ ​​
​​​ ​Ohh…​ ​​
​​​ ​You're actually on the right track.​ ​​
​​​ ​But the real question is what--​ ​​
​​​ ​B-L-A-F-F-U-O.​ ​​
​​​ ​Buffalo is in New York.​ ​​
​​​ ​Okay!!​ ​​
​​​ ​That actually makes a lot of sense.​ ​​
​​​ ​Can we check it?​ ​​
​​​ ​I swear I DID NOT help them.​ ​​
​​​ ​Now, they may have solved ​ ​​
​​ ​that puzzle for you,​ ​​
​​​ ​but it wasn't exactly smooth sailing ​ ​​
​​ ​for all my other friends.​ ​​
​​​ ​The angry lot?…​ ​​
​​​ ​Lair…?​ ​​
​​​ ​It's kind of cool.​ ​​
​​​ ​Let me try to do the clue before ​ ​​
​​ ​everyone else does it!!​ ​​
​​​ ​Maybe it's a parking lot?​ ​​
​​​ ​Fifty… Fourty-nine, fifty-eight!​ ​​
​​​ ​That's the-- ​ ​​
​​ ​That's a thing.​ ​​
​​​ ​Well, Sketch, at least you tried.​ ​​
​​​ ​Quackity then got this sword ​ ​​
​​ ​with symbols on it,​ ​​
​​​ ​which when deciphered, ​ ​​
​​ ​you get Tierra del Fuego.​ ​​
​​​ ​Airrack's gift decoded to ​ ​​
​​ ​Algiers, Algeria.​ ​​
​​​ ​Hayley Baylee's rings got you ​ ​​
​​ ​DeKalb, Illinois.​ ​​
​​​ ​And the totally real diamond ​ ​​
​​ ​that Chris Hemsworth stole​ ​​
​​​ ​got you Queensland, Australia.​ ​​
​​​ ​After those, if you went to ​ ​​
​​ ​our website,​ ​​
​​​ ​you'd see the final and biggest gift ​ ​​
​​ ​in this photo.​ ​​
​​​ ​And hopefully you notice these panels ​ ​​
​​ ​with weird symbols,​ ​​
​​​ ​which are actually numbers using ​ ​​
​​ ​a special code called Tor'oc.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you convert these symbols, ​ ​​
​​ ​you get numbers​ ​​
​​​ ​which spells out ​ ​​
​​ ​"a nice sugar."​ ​​
​​​ ​The word "nice" is referring to ​ ​​
​​ ​a place in France called Nice,​ ​​
​​​ ​and the French word for sugar ​ ​​
​​ ​is "sucre,"​ ​​
​​​ ​which brings you to Sucre, ​ ​​
​​ ​a place in Bolivia.​ ​​
​​​ ​Group four is where things got BIG.​ ​​
​​​ ​How big?​ ​​
​​​ ​Salesforce Tower big.​ ​​
​​​ ​Group four was all about outreach.​ ​​
​​​ ​By counting how many seconds​ ​​
​​​ ​each color stayed on ​ ​​
​​ ​on top of the tower​ ​​
​​​ ​and mapping those numbers to ​ ​​
​​ ​the letters of the alphabet,​ ​​
​​​ ​it spelled out a clue leading to ​ ​​
​​ ​Silver Coast, Portugal.​ ​​
​​​ ​We even had questions hidden ​ ​​
​​ ​in billboards.​ ​​
​​​ ​After solving those,​ ​​
​​​ ​you'd find even more puzzles hidden ​ ​​
​​ ​in our behind-the-scenes videos.​ ​​
​​​ ​In this video, you can see these ​ ​​
​​ ​incomplete equations on the wall.​ ​​
​​​ ​Using the sub count ​ ​​
​​ ​that flashed at the beginning​ ​​
​​​ ​to complete the equation, ​ ​​
​​ ​you'll get these numbers,​ ​​
​​​ ​which convert to "iturup" ​ ​​
​​ ​using ASCII.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you continue to look through ​ ​​
​​ ​these videos,​ ​​
​​​ ​you'd find three more locations.​ ​​
​​​ ​This Super Bowl ticket ​ ​​
​​ ​we gave to a fan​ ​​
​​​ ​actually switches to say South Pole​ ​​
​​​ ​instead of Super Bowl ​ ​​
​​ ​in one of our shorts.​ ​​
​​​ ​Speaking of shorts, ​ ​​
​​ ​this one was definitely popular.​ ​​
​​​ ​Early on, a lot of people ​ ​​
​​ ​found this hidden message​ ​​
​​​ ​in the capital letters ​ ​​
​​ ​of this paragraph.​ ​​
​​​ ​It spelled out, ​ ​​
​​ ​"This means nothing.​ ​​
​​​ ​I just wanted to waste your time ​ ​​
​​ ​L-O-L."​ ​​
​​​ ​But see, that's just what ​ ​​
​​ ​I wanted you to think,​ ​​
​​​ ​'cuz if you notice the key on ​ ​​
​​ ​the cow walking a cow,​ ​​
​​​ ​the numbers on the basketball jerseys,​ ​​
​​​ ​the Slack message from the bear,​ ​​
​​​ ​the pound symbol on the boxer's hat,​ ​​
​​​ ​and the fact that all these ​ ​​
​​ ​butlers have doors,​ ​​
​​​ ​you would reasonably discover that​ ​​
​​​ ​we were probably just trying to say ​ ​​
​​ ​Quito, Ecuador.​ ​​
​​​ ​Right…?​ ​​
​​​ ​Later on, our friends over ​ ​​
​​ ​at Lone Shark Games​ ​​
​​​ ​would post three different puzzles ​ ​​
​​ ​to their socials.​ ​​
​​​ ​Upon solving, you'd get ​ ​​
​​ ​three different locations.​ ​​
​​​ ​At this point, the puzzle was only ​ ​​
​​ ​half complete,​ ​​
​​​ ​and this next group was massive.​ ​​
​​​ ​It all started at a secret website ​ ​​
​​ ​called beast.travel​ ​​
​​​ ​where their next forty puzzles ​ ​​
​​ ​were waiting.​ ​​
​​​ ​Beast Travel featured five sections, ​ ​​
​​ ​each including a unique set of puzzles.​ ​​
​​​ ​Three of which were already ​ ​​
​​ ​unlocked when you arrived.​ ​​
​​​ ​There was Trips By Car which had ​ ​​
​​ ​fifteen picture puzzles called rebuses.​ ​​
​​​ ​Like this one here​ ​​
​​​ ​with a gate, a scale, ​ ​​
​​ ​and a scary Grim Reaper.​ ​​
​​​ ​This is how you decode it.​ ​​
​​​ ​This is a Gate-Weigh to Death Valley,​ ​​
​​​ ​which is the nickname for Beatty, Nevada.​ ​​
​​​ ​Next up, Trips By Horse.​ ​​
​​​ ​This section was loaded with riddles ​ ​​
​​ ​we called "cryptic trios."​ ​​
​​​ ​Solve the three clues on a card,​ ​​
​​​ ​and you get a random three-word combo ​ ​​
​​ ​like this one.​ ​​
​​​ ​A pushed down sequel to "Myst" is ​ ​​
​​ ​"Driven,"​ ​​
​​​ ​thing in this hunt is a "Hint,"​ ​​
​​​ ​and a little devil wandering and ​ ​​
​​ ​getting better is "Improving."​ ​​
​​​ ​Driven, Hint, Improving.​ ​​
​​​ ​Sounds like nonsense​ ​​
​​​ ​until you type it into ​ ​​
​​ ​this geocoding website like this.​ ​​
​​​ ​And it's another location pin.​ ​​
​​​ ​We literally used ​ ​​
​​ ​a global coordinate system,​ ​​
​​​ ​which codes in three-word combos ​ ​​
​​ ​to hide nine new locations.​ ​​
​​​ ​Kind of insane.​ ​​
​​​ ​heh hee…​ ​​
​​​ ​And that third unlocked group ​ ​​
​​ ​was Trips By Plane,​ ​​
​​​ ​which contain sixteen puzzles ​ ​​
​​ ​known as GeoGuessrs.​ ​​
​​​ ​A game made possible by Google Earth​ ​​
​​​ ​and the ability to see all over the world ​ ​​
​​ ​at any given time.​ ​​
​​​ ​These sixteen GeoGuessrs,​ ​​
​​​ ​the nine cryptic crosswords,​ ​​
​​​ ​and fifteen rebuses​ ​​
​​​ ​made up a total of forty ​ ​​
​​ ​new puzzles to solve.​ ​​
​​​ ​Put that together with ​ ​​
​​ ​the fifty-one locations​ ​​
​​​ ​uncovered in stages one through four,​ ​​
​​​ ​and there's a pretty obvious question:​ ​​
​​​ ​What do you do with a list of ​ ​​
​​ ​ninety-one random locations?​ ​​
​​​ ​Well…​ ​​
​​​ ​you have to solve a crossword puzzle ​ ​​
​​ ​to find out.​ ​​
​​​ ​Off we GO!!​ ​​
​​​ ​On Super Bowl Sunday, we released ​ ​​
​​ ​a giant crossword with zero clues.​ ​​
​​​ ​As the challenge went on, ​ ​​
​​ ​clues randomly appeared.​ ​​
​​​ ​Solving this crossword was the key ​ ​​
​​ ​to unlocking the entire game.​ ​​
​​​ ​It also came with this weird ​ ​​
​​ ​eleven level array of empty blocks,​ ​​
​​​ ​which nobody knew what it meant ​ ​​
​​ ​until I revealed 167 across.​ ​​
​​​ ​What this puzzle commemorates in ​ ​​
​​ ​eleven words in the theme entries.​ ​​
​​​ ​The answer was a pun, ​ ​​
​​ ​Souper Bowl Sunday.​ ​​
​​​ ​Now players knew what to look for: ​ ​​
​​ ​soup themed words.​ ​​
​​​ ​Once extracted, these words actually ​ ​​
​​ ​fit the array,​ ​​
​​​ ​and a new clue emerged... ​ ​​
​​ ​the phrase "titanic hoop."​ ​​
​​​ ​You might be asking,​ ​​
​​​ ​what on earth is a titanic hoop?​ ​​
​​​ ​Try a little word association.​ ​​
​​​ ​"Titanic" means great, ​ ​​
​​ ​and "hoop" means circle.​ ​​
​​​ ​Put it together and ​ ​​
​​ ​you get a great circle,​ ​​
​​​ ​the absolute largest circle ​ ​​
​​ ​that can be drawn on a sphere,​ ​​
​​​ ​which on Earth is the equator.​ ​​
​​​ ​So, the next logical step​ ​​
​​​ ​was connecting our giant list ​ ​​
​​ ​of ninety-one locations​ ​​
​​​ ​using great circles ​ ​​
​​ ​on the actual globe.​ ​​
​​​ ​The problem was the possibilities ​ ​​
​​ ​were endless.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you were smart,​ ​​
​​​ ​you made your way back ​ ​​
​​ ​to beast.travel,​ ​​
​​​ ​where Trips By Boat was unlocked ​ ​​
​​ ​and waiting.​ ​​
​​​ ​Inside was a long list of ​ ​​
​​ ​fill-in-the-blank puzzles,​ ​​
​​​ ​each including either a car, horse, ​ ​​
​​ ​plane, or boat.​ ​​
​​​ ​And having collected ​ ​​
​​ ​just as many locations​ ​​
​​​ ​at this point in the game,​ ​​
​​​ ​as this list is long,​ ​​
​​​ ​players got started filling ​ ​​
​​ ​in the blanks.​ ​​
​​​ ​When all the transportation symbols ​ ​​
​​ ​were aligned like so,​ ​​
​​​ ​there was a new clue ​ ​​
​​ ​just beneath the surface.​ ​​
​​​ ​It was instructions ​ ​​
​​ ​for the next puzzle​ ​​
​​​ ​and a good indication of ​ ​​
​​ ​where to find it.​ ​​
​​​ ​The final unlocked beast.travel section, ​ ​​
​​ ​Trips By Roamy.​ ​​
​​​ ​A poem there hinted of three points ​ ​​
​​ ​of embarkation,​ ​​
​​​ ​and this example connecting ​ ​​
​​ ​Haley Baylee,​ ​​
​​​ ​one cryptic trio,​ ​​
​​​ ​and a bonus crossword answer​ ​​
​​​ ​did represent three locations.​ ​​
​​​ ​DeKalb, Illinois,​ ​​
​​​ ​Manistee, Michigan,​ ​​
​​​ ​and Eyjafjallajokull volcano in Iceland.​ ​​
​​​ ​heh HA!​ ​​
​​​ ​That's a mouthful!​ ​​
​​​ ​But it turns out, ​ ​​
​​ ​those three locations​ ​​
​​​ ​did fall perfectly on a great circle.​ ​​
​​​ ​Here's how it worked.​ ​​
​​​ ​The forty locations collected ​ ​​
​​ ​at beast.travel​ ​​
​​​ ​were connections ​ ​​
​​ ​between answer pairs​ ​​
​​​ ​from the first stage of ​ ​​
​​ ​the challenge, like so.​ ​​
​​​ ​Beatty, Nevada connected ​ ​​
​​ ​Tijuana, Mexico​ ​​
​​​ ​to Yellowknife, Northwest Territories.​ ​​
​​​ ​L'Ascension in Quebec connected ​ ​​
​​ ​Yellowknife, Northwest Territories​ ​​
​​​ ​to Montreal, Quebec.​ ​​
​​​ ​This final grid was actually a tool​ ​​
​​​ ​to organize all the locations ​ ​​
​​ ​players had gathered,​ ​​
​​​ ​and when complete,​ ​​
​​​ ​they had a properly ordered list​ ​​
​​​ ​to tie all these locations together.​ ​​
​​​ ​They noticed something.​ ​​
​​​ ​These weren't just random lines.​ ​​
​​​ ​This is an R.​ ​​
​​​ ​Look closely.​ ​​
​​​ ​This is sixty-two.​ ​​
​​​ ​They were literally spelling out ​ ​​
​​ ​the one million dollar vault code.​ ​​
​​​ ​As they worked their way ​ ​​
​​ ​through the list,​ ​​
​​​ ​plotting point after point ​ ​​
​​ ​and line after line,​ ​​
​​​ ​a pattern turned up ​ ​​
​​ ​in the code.​ ​​
​​​ ​R62L39R05.​ ​​
​​​ ​It didn't take long before players ​ ​​
​​ ​started submitting this combo​ ​​
​​​ ​as the final vault code.​ ​​
​​​ ​But unfortunately for them, ​ ​​
​​ ​it still wasn't complete.​ ​​
​​​ ​And fortunately for me,​ ​​
​​​ ​I got to keep my one million bucks ​ ​​
​​ ​a little bit longer.​ ​​
​​​ ​Two final clues were still left ​ ​​
​​ ​to crack this challenge​ ​​
​​​ ​once and for all.​ ​​
​​​ ​The first one had been hiding in ​ ​​
​​ ​plain sight all along at beast.travel.​ ​​
​​​ ​And the second one, ​ ​​
​​ ​I actually dropped​ ​​
​​​ ​the day after the Super Bowl ​ ​​
​​ ​on Good Morning America,​ ​​
​​​ ​when Michael Strahan asked me this.​ ​​
​​​ ​Between you and I, ​ ​​
​​ ​can you give me a hint?​ ​​
​​​ ​Soo, uMmm…​ ​​
​​​ ​tskk…​ ​​
​​​ ​Well…​ ​​
​​​ ​I guess that's a no, man.​ ​​
​​​ ​ahh hah HAHH!​ ​​
​​​ ​huahh hah ha haaa…​ ​​
​​​ ​No, no, Michael.​ ​​
​​​ ​Let's just flush out ​ ​​
​​ ​the other clue first.​ ​​
​​​ ​Every map puzzle at beast.travel​ ​​
​​​ ​was paired with a unique ​ ​​
​​ ​twelve-letter word.​ ​​
​​​ ​These were real words you can ​ ​​
​​ ​literally find in the dictionary,​ ​​
​​​ ​but until now, ​ ​​
​​ ​they were pretty meaningless.​ ​​
​​​ ​Here's the trick.​ ​​
​​​ ​When they're stacked like this,​ ​​
​​​ ​the first letters spell ​ ​​
​​ ​a secret message.​ ​​
​​​ ​This stack spells "numbers,"​ ​​
​​​ ​but that was only part ​ ​​
​​ ​of the story.​ ​​
​​​ ​Stack the remaining thirty-four words,​ ​​
​​​ ​and you reveal the final clue.​ ​​
​​​ ​"Numbers for this half would smell ​ ​​
​​ ​as sweet as one."​ ​​
​​​ ​If you're wondering ​ ​​
​​ ​what the heck that means,​ ​​
​​​ ​one guy would have ​ ​​
​​ ​figured it out instantly,​ ​​
​​​ ​but he's dead.​ ​​
​​​ ​Sir William Shakespeare,​ ​​
​​​ ​the guy who wrote ​ ​​
​​ ​Romeo and Juliet​ ​​
​​​ ​and this famous line.​ ​​
​​​ ​"What's in a name?​ ​​
​​​ ​That which we call a rose ​ ​​
​​ ​by any other name​ ​​
​​​ ​would smell as sweet."​ ​​
​​​ ​Yeah, we put Shakespeare ​ ​​
​​ ​in this challenge.​ ​​
​​​ ​And not only that…​ ​​
​​​ ​Back to you, Michael.​ ​​
​​​ ​Between you and I, can you give me a hint?​ ​​
​​​ ​ahh heh haa!​ ​​
​​​ ​Maybe look for some numbers in photos​ ​​
​​​ ​that I took at the Super Bowl or something.​ ​​
​​​ ​I don't know.​ ​​
​​​ ​Aaand that was it.​ ​​
​​​ ​If you saw that interview and​ ​​
​​​ ​dug through my Super Bowl ​ ​​
​​ ​Instagram photos,​ ​​
​​​ ​you finally had every ​ ​​
​​ ​piece of the puzzle.​ ​​
​​​ ​Because this specific photo right here​ ​​
​​​ ​wasn't just the only one ​ ​​
​​ ​with numbers,​ ​​
​​​ ​it featured Rosé from Blackpink.​ ​​
​​​ ​And you'd remember, ​ ​​
​​ ​numbers for this half​ ​​
​​​ ​would smell as sweet as one.​ ​​
​​​ ​And if you'd come this far,​ ​​
​​​ ​you were one out of ​ ​​
​​ ​seventy million people​ ​​
​​​ ​who tried to solve ​ ​​
​​ ​this massive challenge,​ ​​
​​​ ​and you were on the verge of claiming ​ ​​
​​ ​the one million dollar prize.​ ​​
​​​ ​On that jet is the person who thinks ​ ​​
​​ ​they've solved the puzzle.​ ​​
​​​ ​Is this Colin?​ ​​
​​​ ​Nice to meet you.​ ​​
​​​ ​Hey, hey!​ ​​
​​​ ​Thank you, man.​ ​​
​​​ ​The vault is right over here.​ ​​
​​​ ​Do you have the code?​ ​​
​​​ ​AHhh…​ ​​
​​​ ​I have the code!​ ​​
​​​ ​How many hours have you put into ​ ​​
​​ ​solving these puzzles?​ ​​
​​​ ​Hundreds and hundreds.​ ​​
​​​ ​Okay…​ ​​
​​​ ​If you input the correct ​ ​​
​​ ​thirty-digit code,​ ​​
​​​ ​that million dollars is yours.​ ​​
​​​ ​hOooo…​ ​​
​​​ ​The most important number ​ ​​
​​ ​of my life.​ ​​
​​​ ​You have it memorized?? ​ ​​
​​ ​You didn't even write it down?​ ​​
​​​ ​I've got it memorized, man.​ ​​
​​​ ​I see it in my sleep.​ ​​
​​​ ​R-62…​ ​​
​​​ ​L-39…​ ​​
​​​ ​Your fingers are shaking!​ ​​
​​​ ​Wait, hold your hand ​ ​​
​​ ​out like this.​ ​​
​​​ ​ah heh he!!​ ​​
​​​ ​It's a MILLION DOLLAR combination!​ ​​
​​​ ​R…​ ​​
​​​ ​0-5…​ ​​
​​​ ​Oh, gosh.​ ​​
​​​ ​L-73…​ ​​
​​​ ​The score was 6 to 0.​ ​​
​​​ ​Yep!​ ​​
​​​ ​Foul on the play, number 66.​ ​​
​​​ ​Uh-huh!​ ​​
​​​ ​Quarter two.​ ​​
​​​ ​Uh-huh…​ ​​
​​​ ​3:09 on the clock.​ ​​
​​​ ​Ball… on the 12.​ ​​
​​​ ​Million dollars.​ ​​
​​​ ​And the rest is some stats ​ ​​
​​ ​I don't quite understand.​ ​​
​​​ ​0-0-3, 0-0…​ ​​
​​​ ​Enter.​ ​​
​​​ ​hee HEH!​ ​​
​​​ ​Access GRANTED!!​ ​​
​​​ ​Boys, OPEN IT UP!!​ ​​
​​​ ​You're the first person ​ ​​
​​ ​in the entire world​ ​​
​​​ ​to put in the code!!​ ​​
​​​ ​WOOo HOOOooOOO!!​ ​​
​​​ ​HAA HA HEhhH!​ ​​
​​​ ​This is the hardest thing ​ ​​
​​ ​I've EVER done.​ ​​
​​​ ​My son's goin' to college!​ ​​
​​​ ​You brought your wife?​ ​​
​​​ ​She is here!​ ​​
​​​ ​Would you say the hobby paid off?​ ​​
​​​ ​It did.​ ​​
​​​ ​HEh haa HAaa HAH!​ ​​
​​​ ​hehh heHH HA!​ ​​
​​​ ​With around ninety locations and ​ ​​
​​ ​one million dollars on the line,​ ​​
​​​ ​I really didn't think anyone ​ ​​
​​ ​would solve this puzzle,​ ​​
​​​ ​but Colin and his team did.​ ​​
​​​ ​And this puzzle proves that ​ ​​
​​ ​nothing is ever what it seems,​ ​​
​​​ ​including this video.​ ​​
​​​ ​Because as I mentioned earlier,​ ​​
​​​ ​there is a puzzle hidden ​ ​​
​​ ​within this video​ ​​
​​​ ​created by Colin himself,​ ​​
​​​ ​and the first person ​ ​​
​​ ​to answer correctly​ ​​
​​​ ​wins $10,000.​ ​​
​​​ ​So if you think you've solved it,​ ​​
​​​ ​scan this QR code and ​ ​​
​​ ​enter your final answer.​ ​​
​​​ ​And as always,​ ​​
​​​ ​thank you for watching ​ ​​
​​ ​this very special video.​ ​​